Excuse me?
I'm a little bit late.
I apologize.
I was waiting for my coffee to finish.
It's become a ritual now.
It used to be coke, now it's coffee, because I don't drink coke anymore.
And water was too boring.
How's it going?
Do echo voice?
Okay.
I'll do an echo voice.
Just for you, my child.
You all mean a great deal to me.
Sounds like angel.
You know what that means, right?
We're going angel today.
I like this guy saying, please do brimstone run.
As if I have a choice.
I will take brimstone if it happens.
Of course, I mean, who wouldn't?
I'm always ready for that.
Now, it's not brimstone.
He's not.
He's a, you know, dumbed down version of brimstone.
It's not quite the same.
You can't play space invaders with him.
Timu brimstone, exactly.
Dollar store.
Oh, God, I ran out of papers.
One sec.
I got more ammo.
That's Hazel's socks.
No, no, no, he blows.
All kinds of good stuff out of his mouth.
Actually out of his eyes, I guess.
Yeah.
And it's good.
It's delicious.
Okay, guys, where's this music from?
Go quick.
You need to know this.
It's, you can't get it wrong.
Guys.
Someone said Rimworld.
Good choice.
But that's not it.
It's actually high guard.
Yes, I've been playing it on ironically.
Like, I'm addicted to that.
I can't stop playing it.
Nah, it's from Starcraft 2, man.
Come on.
Yeah, it's Starcraft 2.
It's the Terran theme.
You guys need some educating up in here.
Always going on about me having played X or Y.
Well, you haven't played set, okay?
Don't talk to me if you haven't played Starcraft.
That's all I'm saying.
Also, who wants to want to be one of me in Starcraft?
We're all uncultured to some degree.
Like, I have blind spots in my gaming backlog as well, okay?
Until very recently, I never played Zelda, and that's kind of crazy in a way.
But here we are.
They want to be one in real life.
No, they're not loose.
That's why I'm asking for Starcraft.
I would lose on a 1v1 in real life for sure, unless I had a gun or something.
And even then, I don't even know how to operate a gun.
They're probably just pulling the trigger, but there's safety mechanisms on that shit and you have to reload.
I don't know how to do that.
Okay, let's play some Isaac.
One second.
Okay.
Are thou ready?
I kind of hope I'm going to find an item today that...
Or... hmm, how do I say this?
An item where the mouse can come in handy.
Because I activated the mouse last time and, well, it's not that great.
But I haven't tried an item that is good with it yet, so we'll see.
Okay.
The Golden God, that's me, is going to continue his escapades.
Last time was insane.
A crazy amount of new areas, new bosses out of nowhere.
Well, not out of nowhere, I guess.
We did beat Delirium, which was kind of a big one.
So that probably had something to do with it.
I think I'm going to go ahead and do a random.
A good old random to start off the day.
Because we have a win streak of one.
Guys, the plan is to try and get a win streak of three today.
Win streak of three.
You have to believe in me.
Let's do this.
Oh, shit.
Guys, the goal is to keep a win streak of one.
Okay.
Win streak of one.
Let me see here.
Gain damage up for the current room, right?
We got to play perfectly to move this out of the way.
There we go.
Also, this cursor will disappear after a while, I think, if I don't touch it.
Here we go.
I need, like, 20 minutes to get back into the groove of things here, okay?
Ooh, a fiber.
Just like that.
Cheap labor.
Uh, wait.
I don't have a key.
Oi!
Not bad?
Good start.
Don't tip me like this, man.
I need bombs.
Or flying or something.
This guy needs to die.
Wait, did they walk into the fire?
I think this is what just happened.
We go meticulous now.
If we want to get a win streak, we got to play slow and meticulous, man.
Like, I'm not kidding.
I am going for perfect play today.
Now, see, I could open this, but I'm going to save my key for a treasure room.
Get away from me.
There it is.
No key required.
That's nice.
Oh, you bastard.
Minus tears.
Fires four tears at once in an arc pattern.
Uh, in an arc pattern?
I don't remember.
I got to see it.
Oh, that's good!
That's the shotgun style.
I like that.
Going in here is the death as Judas.
Not a good idea.
Oh, yeah.
Feels good.
The knockback on it is really nice.
Okay, here.
Nine coins.
Would love to get this one.
We got a treasure map.
I could do one of these.
There's a heart over here.
I could get super lucky.
Okay, not super lucky.
Worth a shot, though.
All right, let's keep moving.
Get this one.
Uh, the- Oh!
We could go into the curse room now.
If we wanted to.
Oh, wait!
This is it!
That's it!
I forgot about these coins.
Yeah!
Very nice.
And now we can afford it!
It is actually just called a treasure map.
Fully visible map.
But it's not gonna show me secrets.
Shit.
Okay, let me try and see.
Secrets is probably...
I don't have a bomb, but it would be here, I guess.
It's always sort of like in the center.
Surrounded by as many rooms as possible.
Oh, no, don't.
No, don't do that.
No, look at all these chests!
Oh, man.
This is a tough boss.
I'm not sure I can do this.
Oh, nevermind.
We can do it.
Wasn't that hard.
Extra range?
Could be handy with the- Oh, wait, wait!
Is this just always the case now?
That I can do, except I can't.
I don't have a key.
Shit.
Uh, I could go into the...
What do you call it?
The curse room.
Maybe I get super lucky in there.
It is super risky, though.
Because we're gonna be at half an HP.
Oh, this may be a mistake.
We have the Fool, right?
So we can just get out.
Come on, please.
Cursed Eye.
Charge shot that fires up to- Wait, how does that work with the one I currently have?
Taking damage, mid-charge, tell- Oh, no!
I don't like the second part!
That's bad!
Nope!
I'm out of there.
Fuck that noise.
Nope, nope, nope.
Nothing I can get in here, anyway.
Okay, guess we're moving on with half an HP.
One hit and I'm down.
God, I feels bad leaving all these chests behind, though.
Poop present.
Okay, let's see here.
Uh, 100% demon mode and we have the layout.
I think I'm gonna go north first.
Oh my god.
Oh, scary.
I need healing, man.
What is this room?
I have bad feelings about this.
Where are you going?
Okay, okay.
Bombs?
Call me crazy.
Right here.
Watch.
Yeah, baby.
But now we need healing.
Nice.
So far, so good.
I really regret making that play going into the curse room.
I'm gonna use it here.
I'm scared.
Okay, we got a bomb.
No tinted rocks, unfortunately.
No!
The boss!
We can't do it yet.
Go back.
Wow, that was scary.
Uh, let's go here.
Uh, okay.
Sure, I'll take that.
How about some HP?
Okay, I can give these guys a couple bombs, I guess.
Give me HP, man.
Oh, okay, I mean, that's fine.
Lucky Penny, nice.
Oh, crap.
Oof.
Scary.
Fucking streak is gone.
Fuck.
God damn it, man.
Judas is so fucking difficult.
You have, like, no room for error at all on that character.
It's crazy.
Okay, so what about this one?
No items?
Uh, dodge that.
Man, that was so sad.
It was such a good run, too, if you think about it.
I had good money.
I found a treasure map and shit.
Ah!
I'm okay.
Whoa.
Come on.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Jump at me.
Uh, I can't get to that.
Ooh, that's good!
We like that one.
I always think it's the Bible when I see it.
Because it looks like the Bible.
Okay, we got bombs.
Uh, I think this is worth it.
Hell yeah.
There's also a step room in case we want to go dancing.
The drive-by method.
I have good damage on this character.
Four damage.
Like, that's really good.
Go north.
No tinted rocks.
One at a time, one at a time.
I think I'm hitting something.
Oh my god, man.
Good hit.
How is this not one of the hardest rooms ever made?
Like, this is way harder than a lot of bosses.
Absolute insanity.
Some of these rooms.
Oh my god!
That was tough.
No tinted?
Come here.
Oh, I also want to do speedruns today, actually.
I want to do boss rush.
Get a free item.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, calm down.
Do that again.
Oh my god, two soul hearts as well on top of it all?
I'll take it.
What about this?
A singular coin.
Could buy a bomb, I guess, if I wanted.
Dude, we could go step with this.
We can use up a bunch of blue hearts.
Is it worth it?
Probably not right now.
There's got to be more step rooms later.
There's no rush.
Okay, maybe it's not worth it to try and kill those flies.
Just kill the guy.
Maybe he only spawns a max of two?
He just ran into his own fly.
Nice.
Oh, I hate this item.
It's so boring.
It's so vanilla, you know?
Uh, sure.
I'll take it.
Obviously, we got to go in here.
This is awesome.
Okay, then we have to use this.
Is there anything else on this floor that I needed to do?
We got four coins, maybe with this one.
Five coins.
Okay, you know what?
I should have saved that until I lost some HP, I think.
Some red HP.
But then again, I could hold on to that forever.
So, nah, I think it's okay.
Cheers, guys.
Downpour.
And we have a really healthy buffer right now.
So, our demon chance is going to stay pretty demon.
That's right.
Uh, I can't get...
Wait, can I...
I wonder if I can blow these up and make a little bridge.
Probably, right?
But I'm not going to do it.
Because I can't get to the center island.
So, too bad.
But, oh, I was like, why can't I enter?
Because there's enemies in here.
Oh, obviously, I do this.
No!
Well, now we took the worst, so it could only go uphill from here.
That's good, I guess.
That multidimensional Bobby.
It is Bobby.
That one is an unknown.
I don't know if I like that one too much.
Um, I think it could be really good if you get that other item that makes it stick.
So, it doesn't rotate, you know?
I want this.
Mongo friend.
Fires tears at Isaac's base tier rate.
Copies the tier effects of other familiars, okay.
One out of three on conjoin.
Also, look at this, there's planks in the wall here.
Would love to blow that up, but I don't have a lot of bombs.
And I'm going to save my key.
Or something else other than the shop.
Oh my god, what is this?
Well, that's new.
Oi, oi, oi.
Wait, do they get smaller?
No, they don't.
Wow.
That's kind of a cool effect.
I like it.
You guys are stuck.
Oh shit, I'm also stuck.
What the...
I got leech drift here.
Teleport to the starting room.
Sure.
I could do that if I find a curse room, which I already did find.
Here.
What are they gonna do?
Okay, I'm not gonna release those bastards.
That's gonna be a bad time.
Now we can really study these guys.
They just have orbitals that shoot projectiles.
Ow, I can't believe I got hit by that.
Okay, dude, this book is gonna be so valuable over time.
The amount of damage I'm gonna be absorbing with that is nuts.
Nah, we go to the room first and then fool out of there.
This is the plan.
Maybe we check out the shop.
It's my last key though.
I'm on...
Nah, leave the shop.
It's gonna be enemy.
No!
Hey, totally worth it.
Okay, now we move on.
Actually, I should go to the shop because what if there's a discount?
We have seven coins, right?
That could be something good in there for the money we have.
But it is my last key, so you know.
I can buy a new key.
God, I want the compass so bad.
Oh, I imagine having the compass early.
Oh my God, I could blow this guy up for some money.
I could blow up this actually.
Get a little bit of money out.
I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna break over the piggy bank just a bit.
Just a bit, because I want this so bad.
I'm gonna buy the key as well.
Because I know if I don't, I'm gonna be sitting on zero keys and I'm gonna be unhappy about that.
Okay.
Wait!
I read it wrong!
I thought it said secret rooms.
Piss!
God fucking damn it, man.
Well, I don't want this item now.
I don't really care about special rooms.
Also, who's this guy?
Ah, he ain't a problem.
He's just acting tough.
Oh, shit.
Okay, there's a lot of little guys here.
I will admit.
Wait, those little leeches can skip across holes in the floor.
Wow!
He angry now.
Dude, that was beautiful!
Never seen this guy before.
Didn't even take damage, baby.
Range lock and a soul heart.
Yeah!
We actually have pretty good range here.
Nice.
Now, I think I'm gonna go for angels.
I'm actually not even gonna enter, guys.
That's right.
Not even gonna peek inside.
I told you, we're going angel today.
Okay, maybe I kind of like the item I got.
I see the special rooms.
I can beeline for that.
That's not bad.
But I still wish it was secret rooms.
Speaking of, I should have looked for some secret rooms in that last floor.
Yeah!
That door is open, baby.
Just for us.
Nice.
And we got it early as well on this floor that's huge.
But wait a minute.
I just had a realization.
It's okay.
I'm not gonna reveal what it was, because it's kind of sad.
I only have one bomb.
Infinite key, so we go in here, of course.
And Gimini.
Wait, wait, wait.
Gimini's gonna be bonding with...
What's the name?
Mongo, baby, right?
Copies the tear effects of other familiars.
This, we don't know what is, of course.
I think I want Gimini.
Ah, but wait, is he meleeing?
He's meleeing, right?
So I wonder if Mongo is gonna go ahead and do melees as well now.
Even though I don't think that's technically a tear, so maybe not.
Let's wait with going in here in case we find another fool.
Oh, Gimini's angry.
Look at that.
He's in fight mode.
Maybe I'll become a familiar master.
Is that in my cards?
Shop room, but no money.
Dude,
let's go full familiar style.
Also, does that guy count as a conjoin thingy?
No, he doesn't.
But this one counts, but this one doesn't.
That's too bad.
And you're gone.
Dude, it's kind of going really well, isn't it?
Like, this is solid.
Uh,
let's see here.
Any tinted rocks?
We got a chest?
I could do that, but that's my last bomb, so maybe not.
I like the detail that these fires are gone, because it's all watery down here, right?
That was the effects of most cards.
That one is a good one.
It's a funny one, but it requires calculating.
And counting to four, which is difficult.
I don't know if I like that.
Man, Gimini is really good against these guys.
He takes them out.
Okay.
Ah, you know what?
We could find a bomb in here.
Let's do it.
Sick.
Nine coins.
I could get this thing now.
I think I'm going to do it.
Yeah.
I think it's broken.
Maybe.
I want to go back and explore everything.
We don't leave any rooms unturned.
Why do we have such crazy knockback?
Is that Gimini?
Oh, we have this weird fire here as well.
There's something about that.
When you walk into it, something crazy happens.
Oh, I don't have any bombs left.
Fuck.
Okay.
Oh, no, no, not this.
Please, please, this, sir.
Okay, good.
Now, how on earth am I going to get to these chests, though?
There's like...
Oh, is that a...
Is that a library?
Wait, what did I...
Hold on.
Oh, no.
Wait, it's revealed.
Wait, hold on.
This is like a special room.
Why is this on the map like that?
We need to do something here.
I don't know what, though.
Okay, let's do the curse room.
We have so many blue hearts, anyway.
It's okay.
No.
Hey, a black heart!
Ah, we're going to lose it, though, now.
Man.
Come on.
Okay, time for the boss.
Ooh, do I use the bomb on this?
Or do I go back to the mirror?
That could be another bomb in here, right?
Yeah, we do both, baby.
But I'm going to do boss first.
Oh, it's this guy, okay.
No problem.
Just stay mobile, I guess.
Sometimes he pops out of the ground right where you're standing, so I don't want that to happen.
Oh, I got hit.
Too bad.
Jiminy is doing great here.
Okay, nice.
Ah, you bastard.
This was almost perfect.
Hey, Jules, they're coming!
Plus one damage and range for Isaac's left eye.
We like that, I think.
Oh, the waffle!
Dude, come on.
This is great.
We got to kill this guy.
You're mine, son!
What are you doing?
You're not doing anything.
You suck!
We're going back.
Wait, uh, oh, wait, wait, wait.
We could also use two bombs here, though.
Oh, let's check if the fight room is open.
Let's see if the fight room is open.
Or we can look for secret rooms as well.
It's not down here.
If anything, it should be here, I guess.
But that is risky.
We have blue hearts, right?
Oh, wait, it's not...
Okay, so it's not about the blue hearts.
But wait, this is also a different room.
This is not the fight club.
This is, I don't know, boss club or something.
Okay, yeah, let's go.
Let's see what happens.
Pay attention.
Oh, it brings bad luck to destroy a mirror!
But, maybe a door is open somewhere.
You know?
Like, not a literal door, but a figurative one, you know?
Okay, one bomb left.
One bomb left.
I think, honestly, it's here.
Right here.
Watch.
Fuck, I'm good!
Actually, crazy gamer.
And we got seven coins now.
I could go back to the shop.
But there's not really anything I want to buy.
Yeah, I'm good.
Dude, if I find a way to see secret rooms, I will eventually, or essentially, have revealed the entire map on every floor.
Which is kind of crazy, right?
Time to leave.
Actually, there's one thing I want to try again.
This weird fire, if you step into it, something happens and I need to understand what's going on.
Wait, I'm flying!
Wait, do I get permanent flying?
There's no way.
Maybe it just lasts for this floor.
I can't believe it's, like, permanent.
There's no way, right?
Okay, let's see.
Also, why is this still...
Uh, can't get in...
Oh, wait, I should have saved my bombs, actually.
I kind of regret.
It's fine.
Move on.
We spent enough time on that floor.
Flooded caves, and we can use two keys here.
Actually, I kind of like knowing where these special rooms are.
I will say that.
I like it.
Get in here.
No way, bro.
The hell is that even?
Let's go towards the treasure room.
Oh, yeah, you're slowed, son!
No, you're pathetic, charge!
It's nothing.
So that's one.
Oi!
Uh, is that worth it?
No, probably not.
Two!
Oh, wait, we can actually make it.
Watch this.
Uh, ah, but wait, no, we gotta go around, it seems.
So that becomes three.
So this is three now.
Ah, we can't make it to the boss on four.
Unfortunately.
Good.
What happened?
Ah, key.
Also use this, of course.
So this is gonna be four now.
Yep.
Actually, nice to have this room slowed.
One.
Two.
Three.
Ah, we can't make it again.
Wait, what are these guys?
Little mushroom people.
Looked like the ones from Super Mario.
Man, I love this slowing effect.
And Gimini is going wild.
Jawbreaker, chance to fire a tooth shot.
Chance increases with luck!
Yeah, we're gonna have trouble with that one.
Let's just say that.
Okay, so we can save up the fourth charge on the boss room, for sure.
So that's what happened that other run, where I had, like, massive negative luck.
I must have destroyed the mirror there.
So this is one.
Two, three, yeah, it works.
This is two.
Oh, wait!
This may be better.
Is that gonna apply to my familiar as well?
Wait, why is this one slow?
This should have been the third.
Oh, man.
Oh, well.
One.
Oh, this homie's gonna be so good against these guys.
Look at that!
Nice.
Then we have two.
I don't have money for any of this.
Hmm.
I could blow this one up, actually.
Let's do it.
Spider mutts!
Oh, we gotta come back with the money, Lebowski!
Also, did I see?
No, never mind.
I definitely want that.
Uh, I think we were at one.
So I can go two, three.
No, wait, one, two.
Hold on.
So this one was slowed, right?
One, two...
Yeah, I know how to do this.
Yep, yep, yep.
One, two...
I'm gonna have a three up here in the north.
I could also get in here, I think.
Yeah, why not?
Power pill?
That's not bad!
Also, every two enemies killed heals Isaac.
Imagine going low on HP and then, uh, running into a bunch of small guys with it.
Could be pretty cool.
Just to heal up, you know?
So this is three now.
Uh, I guess we blow this one up.
Okay.
It's money.
And now we have the slowed boss.
Which could also be a fast boss, by the way.
If we're unlucky.
But it's very unlikely.
Let's see.
Yeah, pestilons!
Oh, you're slow, huh?
That's too bad.
And does he shoot a lot of projectiles?
Oh, I stepped in the creep like an idiot.
We can upgrade the cube of meat!
Huh.
Uh, yeah, I guess.
Oh, I like the song when it's slowed.
That's kind of ominous, isn't it?
Okay, well, we got to go to that curse room.
I wish the song would just keep playing in slowdown.
Let's go up here.
I'm not afraid.
Oh, well, they will hold towards them even when they're invisible.
That's nice.
Wait, uh, I got...
Wait, why do I have the jawbreaker?
Uh, did I accidentally exchange that?
Oh, I thought the spoon replaced the jawbreaker!
I thought the spoon was a goddamn trinket!
Even better!
Hell yeah!
Ah!
Blow him up!
Huge.
That extra key is gonna be nice.
Okay, time to find secrets.
So, check this out.
I think...
There's actually two good options here, I would say.
One here.
Let me check the other sides.
Could be... there's like a little opening.
Okay, I'm actually so sure.
Fuck!
Okay, so it's actually over here.
Uh, let me see.
Does it work?
Let me check the other side.
I could do it.
This one is not, because there's water here.
Now, let me go back in here.
To the spider motto!
Oh, man.
That's so sad.
Okay, it could also be here.
It's not there.
I think it's up here.
I think it's here.
Range up luck that...
I mean, fuck luck at this point.
We don't care about luck.
Nice!
Even smaller!
But now we have the problem where my familiars are bigger than me.
So, that doesn't feel good.
Now, watch.
I'm gonna destroy these with the bomb.
No, no, I'm not actually.
I'm not.
We're gonna find another secret room.
No, we're not.
No, fuck that.
I will get a crazy mushroom now.
Oh, man, 13 coins!
We need two more!
Come on, baby!
Can we somehow cough up two coins, man?
It's gotta be possible.
Wait, power pill.
Can I walk through rocks with that?
Invincibility and contact damage?
Contact damage could be red as you were able to, you know, eat rocks or something.
You can't shoot.
Maybe it's a chest somewhere, maybe.
Oh, man.
Oh, wait, we can't go in here now.
Maybe that's okay.
It's okay.
That's sad.
Ah, whatever.
I'm gonna immediately step into this room.
Oh, I'm glad I did.
Oh, very good, very good.
I got three keys.
I'll use two of them, why not?
We got one back.
Not bad at all.
Big poop.
Wish I could flush him.
Oh my god, we're getting so much good stuff in here.
Ah, I mean, we can slowly work our way up in the lock department, but it's like it's going to be a long road.
It'll take a while.
This guy's tanky AF.
Oh, there's two of them.
Uh-huh.
This is where the good range comes in.
Look how nice this is.
Playing it mega safe here.
Homing tears.
Feels good, man.
Nice.
Ah, so we went northwest, and now we went east, and there's also a south in the other room.
So let's just keep going in like a systematic way here.
These familiars are helping quite a bit.
Giant cell.
Taking damage spawns a mini familiar.
These mini familiars last until destroyed from taking enough damage.
Max of 16 times the familiars.
Okay.
Just keep shooting and hope that the homing tears are doing their job.
This is my game plan right now.
Mama's here.
Oh, she's slowed.
I didn't even notice.
One.
Two.
Three.
The hell is that thing up north?
That's disgusting.
We're going to be slowing down things here.
What a disgusting animal we just saw.
Thank you, Giminy.
Solid.
This is two.
Dude, the tears even like turn around and come back for the enemy.
Three.
And slowed.
Oh, sped up.
Okay.
What a crazy room to speed up though.
No problem.
One.
What the shop's at?
This is a big battery.
I can come back for that and gain more blue hearts if I need to.
I'm not that fast here.
Oh, made it.
No, they took my battery!
Those bastards.
More range.
Nah, I'm good.
I'd rather have the jawbreaker.
But wait, that was dependent on luck, right?
Wait, I wonder if it's 10% baseline and then you can only go up from there.
So I wonder if me having minus six luck right now means that I have 10%.
Maybe 10.1 or something.
I hope it's not going to go down from there.
It's like 2%.
I will say though, I don't see the tooth or the teeth very often.
So maybe this going down.
I think this may be the fourth.
He's going to be slowed now, right?
Yeah.
War.
Nah, nah, nah, nah, nah, nah, nah, nah, nah.
Oh no, that's not how the song goes.
Look how slow he is and he's usually so fast.
That's such a tragedy.
Oh God, bombs are still fast.
That didn't change.
Wait, we gain damage.
Wait a minute.
That's how this character works, right?
Take damage and you gain damage.
So taking damage is actually good, in a way.
I have to remember that.
Okay, Cube of Meat again.
So now it chases and damages enemies.
Wait, it kind of looks like...
Oh wait, is this a reference to Super Meat Boy?
Look at the tooth.
I think it just dawned on me, guys.
I think that's what that is.
It has to be.
Biggest familiar that chases...
Wait, oh, we have a familiar now.
It's not bigger yet, but okay.
Obviously, I want to go down here, but not yet.
We got to go back.
Ah, you fucker.
I will get in.
Thank you.
I'm going to get that blue heart.
So now I'm really lost, though.
This is the problem.
Okay, so we came from here.
We walked all the way around.
And then what?
Is this the only other way it was?
What a detour.
There's still one path south from the starting room.
That I did not explore.
And I think some other paths, too.
Ah, here we go.
I mean, that's a good amount of money right there.
Bombs, more money.
Now I just need a proper shop.
I don't think I went this way yet.
No, I didn't.
Nice.
Wait, any tinted?
Not that I can see.
Hey, Mom.
There's one more path.
And we haven't even looked for secrets.
But that's going to be a little hard to do without the map.
I think this was the starting room.
We have looped all the way back.
Yeah.
Okay.
A bit unfortunate, though.
Should have went that way first.
Ah, wait, this is not the right way.
We go here and then we go all the way around.
We're going to loop up and left and left and up.
I mean, it's going pretty well.
Look at the damage we have and the hearts.
It's going really well.
There's no other way to put it.
I like that my character's glowing slightly.
Makes it easier to see him in the heat of battle.
And then we go here and then we have the...
Let's go in here.
Plus 2.8 damage there.
We have purple fire.
Ah, let me see.
I think I just go.
All right.
Minus 6 damage.
Wait, so we have shitty base damage or what?
Holy shit.
That's really bad.
Obviously we're going to do this.
Oh my god.
That's scary.
Somehow we nailed it, though.
Now to get to that treasure room on the right, I think we got to go probably up.
But you don't really know.
He had bending lasers.
What a mad man.
Also, I just noticed we're not flying anymore.
So it is only for one floor.
Wait, oh, we got to destroy these portals.
One down.
Good stuff.
Now I do have money, but I'm going to save it for the shop, and then we're going to come back to the arcade.
Oh, what the hell?
Insanity.
I mean, we're getting damage every time we take damage, so it's actually not that bad.
And we can recharge it, right?
So yeah, I'm happy about this.
Doubles bombs?
Uh, yeah, why not?
I'm going to save this pill for a rainy day.
Maybe like right now.
Oh my god, I got pushed there.
Sweet.
That was a rainy day just now.
Oh god.
Bring that health back.
God, this Bible is incredible.
But not a Bible.
Kill it.
Wait, my familiar is stuck over here.
What the hell is that?
That sucks.
Oh, we don't know what we're going to get.
Big beautiful fly.
Familiar that bounces around the room and explodes.
Okay, that's cool.
Not super useful though.
I'd rather have something that actively aims for enemies and not just does the DVD logo thing, you know?
Got eight bombs.
I have a strong suspicion that we don't have a secret room there.
On the right.
Can't catch me.
Advanced strategies.
This is one.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Uh, this is going to be two.
I'm going to go in.
Crap.
Oh.
Copies.
Dammit.
Ah, I guess we can do one.
Do one of them and then switch back.
This is two.
Oh, this is three.
Okay, so that was slow.
That was one, two, three.
Yeah, we're on three.
This is going to be slowed now.
Wait, did he just press the button himself?
He made the gym happen.
I didn't even do it.
Ah, I stepped on the bullshit.
That was so bad.
Well, this guy is kind of crazy.
Oh, no.
Gimme, do you mind getting over there?
Oh, wait, I can teleport.
Of course.
Do we do boss?
No, we go to shop first.
I see how it is.
Oh, yo, yo, yo, yo, yo, yo.
At least we're gaining damage.
9.5 damage now.
It's going to go hard.
Oh, these guys are crazy.
As long as you stay like right below them or to the sides, you're fine.
What do we have here?
I'm definitely taking this.
A fanny pack.
Filled with goodies.
50% chance to drop a pickup when taking damage.
Okay, that is a nice synergy with my character in general.
I think I'll take a pill as well, honestly.
I could buy this, too, to get a little bit more battery and then another blue heart.
Why not?
May seem like a waste, but it is a blue heart.
It's fine.
Have so much money anyway.
Okay, this boss is going to feel the pain now.
The heretic!
Oh, my God.
They are doing some kind of demonic ritual.
We don't approve of that.
We cannot be doing that.
Oh, he's spawning fires.
Whoa, oh, cool.
That was a cool attack.
Oh, he's fast, he's fast, he's fast, he's fast.
Wow.
This guy's actually kind of crazy.
You unlocked...
I thought it said Cleveland.
Gehenna.
You unlocked Cleveland.
Matchbook, evil up.
Okay.
Do we want to keep that?
I have 19 bombs, I don't care.
It's angel time, kids!
And we don't know what we're going to get, but that's okay.
Sacred heart, homing shots plus damage up.
Seraphine, minus tears.
Whoa, plus five damage!
Less shot speed, plus one health.
Dude, this thing is crazy?
Holy shit!
That is massive!
Oh, my tears are super big as well.
And look at you being slowed.
Oh, I saw a tooth!
You wish for the tooth to come out?
Key piece two.
Now we have a full key.
We know where to use it.
Let's do...
Yeah, do we want to go to the arcade?
Nah, there's nothing there we would want, right?
That could be.
I'm gonna penny pinch.
Sue me in court.
That's right.
Sue me all you want.
I'm pinching my pennies.
I'm counting my grains.
I just need to take a look inside.
I need to see what's going on.
You know what?
Donate a bunch of HP, because this is such a good combo with my...
spawn item thing as well.
HP plus speed up.
Not bad!
Totally worth coming back, huh?
We're super fast now.
We have minus six luck, so this is gonna be interesting.
Oh, no, okay.
I don't think luck actually affects this, by the way.
I think at this point, it's pretty much confirmed that luck doesn't really matter here.
Because look at that.
I mean, that's great.
That's not so great, though.
That's okay.
Let's blow this up.
Cool.
Look for secrets.
You know what?
Let me blow this up here.
I had a feeling something would happen, okay?
I can't explain it.
Nothing did happen, unfortunately, but that's how the cookie crumbles.
This is not a secret.
This could not be a secret.
Maybe here.
No.
Oh, of course, here.
No, there's a spike.
That probably means there's no...
Where could we have one?
There's a tough one.
It's always near the center, so I think I want to go down a bit over here and then to the right.
So, like, not here, but here.
That could be it.
That's in the very center.
Shit.
Okay, I give up.
I don't want to spend... I do have 22 bombs.
Ah, whatever.
I give up.
Move on.
Curse of the Lost.
Fuck you.
I hate that.
That's the worst.
Kill these demons.
Oh.
Ah, that was a waste.
I can't heal.
Dude, I'm too good.
Actually, I can heal in a second here.
The pact.
Oh, yo!
Not bad at all!
Wow.
That's a great item.
Oh, this is gonna be annoying.
I do wonder if I can destroy this thing.
Ah, crap.
He pushed the bomb into the dude.
Unfortunate.
Samson versus Lust.
Samson is dead.
No, Lust is dead.
Nice.
We love pills.
Pills are so good.
I love that mechanic.
I do wish I had a bit more shot speed.
I'll say that.
That's the only thing.
If I were to nitpick, shot speed would be the thing.
Did you see that dodge?
That was so beautiful.
Ah, but wait, can I actually...
Ooh, okay.
Ah, fuck.
Maybe I can...
Yeah!
I'm tiny enough to do that.
Sick.
Wait, this guy is getting bigger and bigger.
I can't shoot.
I think he just cursed me with something.
Tough love.
Do you have to buy a tooth shot with the...
Ah, this is the luck thing.
And that's a trinket, I believe.
I think I'd rather have this.
Fruitcake.
Okay, that's fine.
Not super excited about that.
Okay.
Wait, I came from here.
This is new.
Have I gone this way?
I have not.
25 coins?
Dreamcatcher.
It's not that exciting, but may as well buy it, right?
Gotta catch them all, as they say.
Someone says it.
I could take damage on purpose right now, guys.
Just so I can get more damage.
And then use my active, because it's just wasted, really.
If you think about it.
This is the one time it makes sense to just take damage.
If there was a step room right now, I would love to do that.
Okay, well, that works.
Yo, wait a minute.
Are these homing effects stacking?
I feel like my tears are homing way more than they used to.
Oh my god.
Hell yeah.
Mom, it slowed down.
What's up, Mom?
Oh my god, my damage is out of control.
Everyone knows it.
Whoa, holy damage.
Wait a minute.
So what do I want here?
So if I take the negative, and I was access to...
I think I'm actually going to take Polaroid, just to switch it up a bit.
Yeah, why not?
Guess we're going to go here.
Oh, but wait, this is the...
I don't know how to get in here.
You know what?
This is going to lead to a room, maybe, or another stage.
And it is to the left of this room.
I have the Fool.
If I can get to the other side and maybe bomb my way in from the other side.
Huh?
The problem is I don't have a map, so I don't really know where things are.
So we're going to have to find the room again and then take it from there.
Oh, we also have this.
Oh, shit, what is this even?
Awkward!
What happened?
Oh, I can't shoot!
They're cursing me!
Good!
Okay, there we go.
Well, that's a weird room.
I think the boss was up here.
This way.
Okay, so the boss is here, which means...
Here?
Fuck.
So, wait, we are plus one right now, plus two.
We're still plus two, plus one.
Now we're here, so here.
Okay, I don't know.
What would I need to get in there?
I even have, like, a key right now on me.
But apparently, that's not it.
Sponsored lots of...
I mean, I can do that, I guess.
Why not?
Oh, another one?
Wow!
All right.
I feel like my luck has nothing to do with the items I find at all.
Yeah.
Okay, I don't know.
Maybe...
Okay, so wait, the door is red, right?
The door is red and there's an X on it.
Or, like, a little crack on it.
So, maybe I need a special bomb to open it.
We know there's, like, a bomb called the Mega Bomb or whatever that blows up everything.
Could be something like that, you know?
Either that, or I stick my PP in that hole.
Which, with this game, I wouldn't be surprised.
Okay, that was inappropriate.
I'm sorry.
I admit it, I'm not above PP jokes.
Get in there.
Ooh, look at this here.
More.
Holy money!
Wait, what was that?
What did I just get?
Oh, Eternal.
We're at max speed.
Weeey!
Sweetness.
And now we finally have a map.
Jesus Christ, that feels good, man.
That feels real good.
Battery?
Sure, why not.
I keep thinking my little blue guy or red guy here is an enemy.
Because he runs after me.
I have pretty good damage here.
That's going really well.
Yeah, look at how many special rooms we have.
Almost none.
Yudero sucks.
Oh, maybe that could be a good thing.
Let's do it.
Why not?
It lives!
Eyes are gone.
Dude, I can sit down here and shoot up.
Look, it's actually not good for my familiars.
That was a waste.
The womb is scarred!
We have angels as well!
A lot of them, I mean, sure.
More damage.
I take that.
I'm gonna fight them.
What you got for me?
What you got?
You ain't got nothing!
You're weak!
You're weak.
Let's go up!
We're gonna send the...
I just used their attacks against them.
The light from above.
Oh crap.
Good to have good move speed now.
Oh, what was that tear effect?
Did you see that?
That was like a giant, I don't know, wave of light or something.
Oh, dude, stop jumping in the holes.
Yeah, having this amount of move speed is actually kind of...
Ah, that was a waste.
I'm a little too eager.
You gonna come out of there?
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
Let's calm it down.
This car is gonna do almost nothing.
I mean, just the amount of DPS I have is so much better than this card.
We can get in here.
I would love to get flying.
That's kind of nice.
Do I want this card?
What do I want?
Wait, is it both death?
Oh, this is the lovers, okay.
Pills?
Health down?
Eh, I don't know about that, son.
I'm good, I'm good.
I'm totally just wasting these hearts, but it feels good to do.
Excess is good for the soul.
Don't let anybody tell you otherwise.
I cannot tell where my character is.
It is a mess.
Okay.
Dude, I think it's gonna be so easy.
He's my specialty, actually.
I just love fighting him.
I know everything he's gonna say, you know, because he's me.
Good.
Oh, man.
What?
Oh, there you are.
Get smaller still?
Why not?
Let's go all the way.
Unidentified.
Ah, that's too bad.
That's a pretty big DPS decrease there.
I cannot tell where my character is, guys.
This is gonna be problematic.
Okay, let's just go for the boss.
No, we wait, we wait.
We're gonna kill everything.
Watch this.
There's too many damn hearts.
Isak!
Oh, you're gonna hit own, son.
I'm just saying.
You're not gonna have a chance against me.
Well, when I can't see my character, then it's kind of difficult.
Legitimately can't see where I am.
Okay, I see myself now.
I see him.
I gotta, like, lock on to my character and not look at anything else.
Yeah, yeah.
What was that?
What?
Why did the sound play?
I don't understand that.
I'll take that.
Wait a minute.
Did these fires change to non-blue fires?
Did that just happen?
Oh,
nice!
I don't...
Oh, well, okay.
There was a short, uh, joy we had there.
Okay.
We kill everything.
I need some kind of freaking arrow on the screen that points to my character.
This is gonna be a problem.
If we're gonna bullet hell, I'm dead.
Joe, what is that tear effect?
That was, like, a Zazelon command.
Missed the... boom, no.
Okay.
What?
Spawn's a large bomb!
Maybe that can be used to open that door.
The red door.
But I'm totally just pulling shit out of my ass, because I really have no clue.
I'm grasping at straws here.
What I'm thinking about is, uh, Majora's Mask right now, and a certain mechanic with different bomb sizes, you know?
Okay, so this fire was not converted.
I guess I'll take that.
No, this one.
I'd rather have that.
Ah, I'm good.
Okay.
So what now?
Are we sped up?
Bloody lust has appeared.
Man, we're just unlocking a bunch of shit.
Oh man, we're so fast.
Lead pencil, every 15 shots, fire a burst of bloody tears.
Uh, could be good.
Toxic shock.
Poisons all enemies at the start of each room.
Destroyed enemies also leave behind a small creep.
Nah.
Lost five bombs, nah.
Wait, what's that?
Key bomb.
He wants your keys.
All right.
Consumes key pickups from the ground and spawns random chests in return.
That sounds cool.
Uh, I guess I'll take this.
Oh wait, I used to take all of them.
Oh shit, I thought it was a choice for some reason.
Slow it down.
Uh, so...
Honestly, I think this is better for me.
Survival is more important right now.
Like, my damage is good.
I don't need more damage.
My character's green, that's nice.
It's kind of nice.
I can see where my character is kinda now.
Not perfect, but it's better.
Wait, who's still alive?
Oh, you're alive.
Another one!
And another one!
That's like the third one.
What's up, fools?
Jesus.
We've reached the stage where I don't even know what's happening with this build.
You know, it's just...
Press the button, hope everything dies.
Wow.
And the wafer is actually gonna be so helpful.
Oh, it has been helpful.
I'm just gonna let the homing take care of these.
I'm not even gonna aim.
Secret room.
Yeah, cool.
Oh my goodness, look at that.
Is that the farty?
The beam!
Well, these are the portion's enemies and the...
No, that sucks.
Lemon mishap.
Uh, if this scales with damage.
You know what?
Let me try it for a bit.
We need to see how good this is right now.
I don't think it does, but...
It could, you know.
Magneto?
Sure.
So we're here now.
Let me try and see.
It doesn't do that much damage, does it?
I was hoping this would almost insta-kill enemies if it scaled with damage.
This doesn't seem to be the case.
Oh, I could be wrong, you know.
I want my other item.
The question is, when do we go through the big old door?
There's a boss here.
I'm afraid of doing that in case I can't come back.
Sometimes you can't come back, you know.
Jeez.
High priestess.
One down.
Oh, I can't see where I am.
I mean, at this point, I feel like it's actually better if I don't.
Because we've reached the point where I'd rather have black hearts, you know.
I think I'm gonna leave them.
It sounds crazy, but I find more blue hearts right now than red hearts.
And black hearts, I guess.
Let's go down.
It just died to the toxic thing.
I think farts are poops every 30 seconds, nah.
I don't need that.
Would love to find a better trinket, though.
I'm not super happy about my current.
It's just a huge sale.
What is it with this room?
If I destroy all the poops without any of them coming back, something happens.
I don't have the DPS for it.
I've got... yeah.
Well, there's not much left to clear.
Yeah, you're dead.
I think right here.
Shit.
Maybe here.
Damn.
Okay, check it out.
We're gonna... we're gonna go in here now.
Oh, that's him!
Oh, fuck!
I'm not ready!
Oh, no.
I can't believe I've done this.
Oh, my god.
Destroy the hands!
Yeah!
It's gonna be a crazy fight, I think.
I'm really focusing on trying to see where my character is.
Oh, look at the green!
Look at the green!
Focus on the green.
Wow.
Get those hands out of here.
Oh, we got a blue guy!
Oh, I stepped on some creep, I think.
I gotta scratch my nose!
Hands are gone.
Angels!
Dark angel!
What the fuck?
Another one.
I've dealt with my fair share of angels this run.
I'm not afraid.
Oh, shit.
He's spawning little guys, I think.
Little guys I'm not seeing.
Good.
Wait, did I just charm his hand?
Why are you hitting yourself?
Dumbass.
Whoa!
He transformed!
He's mega evil now.
I'm not sure how to dodge this one.
Okay, there we go.
That worked.
I'm kind of scared of staying right below him.
Okay, just gonna make lasers.
Good thing I'm homing.
Come on, DVD, I can't do something!
Doing that again.
What are you doing now?
Okay, random shots.
Oh, god.
Oh, goodness gracious.
Are you done now?
Are you done?
Not bad.
Ooh, but wait!
Should we go further?
Or do we open the chest?
Oh my god, I'm gonna go down, I think.
We gotta go further.
And it's slowed down.
Dude, look at all the stages.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, eleven, twelve.
Wait, why is this taking so long?
Oh, it showed me all the bosses, I think.
Rage baby, you unlocked the destroyer.
Challenge three...
Challenge 30...
Dude, unlocks upon unlocks this run.
Crazy.
And there's all the bosses.
Well, time to do a boss rush, I guess.
In a way.
Oh, crap.
What do I need this money for?
Nothing.
I wish I could fly.
But I can make bridges.
Magician.
More homing on one of that stacks.
So I currently have two times homing.
Not sure of that stacks, but with three, maybe even better.
Could be good.
Uh, this way.
Just keep getting hearts.
Yeah, open up.
Not bad.
You got me.
I think I should be destroying these.
I have so many bombs anyway.
Yeah.
Sisters bees, huh?
Well, they ain't no challenge for me.
It's a tannic Bible.
Even better.
Wait, activating this before defeating the current floor's boss.
Why does that work?
Does that replace all the bosses?
Or what?
We, we got to try that.
What the fuck?
I'm so curious about that.
Let's see if it works on all the bosses.
Or if it's only the last boss, so to speak, the big boy.
Wow, they just died to the toxic.
Uh, oh, I thought that was another way to go further down just now.
Jera, I don't think we need this, to be honest.
But I'll carry it around.
Why not?
Okay, we got a boss here.
Triac needs.
I'm going to rock his world.
World status has been rocked.
Oh, we're going to get three out of three on Boogworm.
That is so massive for me.
More tears, right?
Why don't I?
Oh, okay.
Okay, I don't know.
It is good though.
It's good.
It's going to help a lot.
Uh, high priestess.
Keep turning these into black hearts.
Shot speed is good for me.
That's what I've been lacking a little bit.
I'm fully rich now.
I can't get richer.
Come here, come to Papa.
I'm taking them all.
Oh, my phone is activating.
I'm not trying to speak to you.
Stop.
Oh, here we go.
Wait, are we sped up?
We're sped up, baby.
Oh, crap cake.
I'm in danger.
Uh-oh.
Honestly, just dodge and hope for the best.
This is the strategy.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I love the black hole.
Angel time?
Where are you?
There you are.
I'm going to start jumping in a second here.
That range is so helpful right now.
Imagine I had the money equals power right now.
That'd be pretty dope, huh?
Good DPS, good DPS.
Dude, I'm dodging so hard.
I got hit there.
Why did I jinx it?
Mom?
What just happened?
Is there an Eternal Heart that spawned or something?
Oh, yeah.
And you're done, son.
You're done.
Your days are over.
What's going on here?
We lived here.
It's the same cinematic, right?
It's not different.
It didn't change.
Man, that household needs help, man.
They need therapy.
That got me back there.
It is so sad.
At least someone put up a poster though.
Someone cared for Isaac, guys.
That's kind of nice.
Someone cared enough for Isaac to put up a poster.
That means he must have had a friend.
Right?
That's the silver lining here.
Good run, though.
Bloody crown has appeared.
Okay, well, we unlocked a sh- Ooh.
Look at that.
Why has it changed?
This game is so full of mysteries.
I don't know what's happening.
Okay, I'm gonna take a quick break.
Five minutes, and then we're gonna do challenges.
Or maybe greed.
We'll see.
I'll see you in a bit.
No, Jackie.
You can't do that right now.
Down with you.
That wasn't me.
That was Jackie.
Jackie did it.
Okay.
Let's see here.
Uh, challenges.
Man, why is the number eight locked, man?
I feel like I'm missing something.
I guess it's just completely red.
Ooh, these are red.
Hmm.
You know what?
I'm actually on a roll right now.
We have a win streak of one.
I think we can go further with it.
I think we do one more random.
Also, Jacob.
Maybe we unlock this guy by using Jacob's ladder somehow.
That's a reach, but still.
Uh, Bethany...
Wait!
New character!
Apollyon, Voigt!
Wait, when did that happen?
Did that happen just now or maybe earlier?
What the hell?
Definitely doing that.
Frick.
Oh, we're a little devil child.
Voigt.
Consumes any pedestal items in the room.
And triggers the effects of all previously consumed active items?
Wait, consumes any pedestal items?
Triggers the effects of all previously consumed active items.
So if I had a converter, and I use my converter 10 times, I do this and I get 10 uses or...
Consuming a passive item grants a permanent stat boost.
Consuming an active item permanently adds its activation effect to Voigt's activation effect.
Whoa!
Okay.
That is confusing.
We have two hearts, 2.7 damage.
No, 3.5 damage.
Zero luck.
Consuming an active item permanently adds.
So you want to be using these on active items.
But also passive items.
If you don't like, okay, if you don't like the passive item, you use this to get stat boost.
That's the, that's the play, I guess.
This is already tough.
All right, it was fine.
Man, we got to keep this streak going.
I call it a streak.
For me, it is.
We have a win streak of one, okay?
That's very...
Oh my god, how we...
Okay.
Fuck this room.
This room sucks.
Oh, we're going the wrong way, too.
All right, tinted rock, tinted rock.
No bombs, though.
Use diaper, for sure.
No reason not to, right?
Where are my treasure rooms and all the other rooms?
These are all weirdly all normal.
Oh man, I hate this.
Ah!
Okay.
How do you dodge this crap?
I'm actually gonna die.
There goes my streak.
Come on, come on.
We got a treasure room?
You.
Okay.
Three keys is okay.
What the hell is that?
The halo.
Speeds, here's damage range, but...
That is massive.
Well, I don't have any money, so rip.
I could go into this room now, but that's risky.
Nah, we do.
We go, we go, we go.
It's gonna be fine.
Trust.
One, two, three, four, okay.
Shit.
Why is this guy so difficult to hit?
Totally worth going in here.
Too bad I don't have any bombs, man.
There's two tinted rocks and a key just for the taking there.
Oh no.
Fuck!
Go!
Here we go.
Oh my god.
I have a knack for just running into tears, man.
I can't dodge that shit.
If there's tears, you know I'm gonna be absorbing those.
The hardest the boss...
Can't even speak English anymore.
Yeah, just kill me.
Honestly, just kill me.
End the run right...
How?!
How is this happening?!
Fuck this guy, man!
I hate it!
Jesus Christ!
We actually gonna lose?
Fuck me.
You know what it is?
The boss is so stupidly simple that he's hard to beat.
Because he does the most stupid things that you don't expect.
It's like losing to someone in Starcraft who's really bad.
So you see they're built and you go, Oh, he's making that.
That means he's going for X.
But no, he's just bad.
So he's going for something else completely and then you lose because you didn't expect that stuff, you know?
Hey!
Healing!
Fuck yeah!
We're back!
Wait, what is this shit?
What are these enemies?
They're like little fishes.
Okay, as long as I stay here on the side, they're not going to hurt me, right?
Wait, did I keep spawning?
Dude!
Uh...
Are you fucking kidding me?
Okay, this guy needs to die.
Why is this so insanely difficult?
Oh, it's this weird room.
I want that chest though.
No bombs.
There's a tinted rock!
Don't do me dirty like this.
Got no money either.
Uh, I think it's worth to go in though.
Oh wait, there's no fires.
Charged baby!
Weird.
I need bombs.
So I wonder if using my item in here is going to do anything.
Let me see, consumes any pedestal items in the room.
No, these are not pedestal items.
These are just items.
Tools or whatever you want to call it.
Here we go.
Let me see, Leo.
He can break most obstacles by...
That's not bad.
I like that actually.
I'm taking that.
Oh, you know...
Okay, don't eat the buckets.
I learned my lesson.
Apparently that's bad for you.
Uh oh.
Look at this guy's hair.
He had a broom on his head.
Okay, boss is here.
That's...
We need healing.
There's no healing to be had.
And no bombs at all, man.
This is just crazy.
We're gonna die here, I think.
I can't beat this guy without taking damage, I'm pretty sure.
Crazy.
We gotta try this character again, though.
We gotta do it again.
At this time, without taking a million damage for no reason.
Fucking win streak is gone now, man.
That was such a good run we had before and now this, you know?
Makes me so sad.
What do we even do here?
I guess we should do that.
Oh!
That is very nice.
We can break things.
Uh, maybe we break the pot, actually.
Sometimes there's items in there.
Yes.
Nice!
Okay, I like this.
And we can probably break tinted rocks as well, if we find them.
Uh, let me see here.
Okay.
Yo!
It's already paying off.
Okay, this guy is always dangerous.
Kill the small guy first.
Come on, man.
These have to be one of the most annoying enemies in the game.
I think I hate them even more than the little guys that pop out of the ground.
And then hide again.
Oh, shit.
That's not gonna make it good.
I could maybe get in there.
Yeah, I can.
It's gonna take a little bit of patience, but it's worth it.
Sweet!
Twelve coins!
Mom's purse is not bad!
Thirteen coins now?
Or we grab the blue heart.
The blue heart is really nice as well, actually.
Just for that buffer.
But it's not important, yes.
I mean, for survival it is, but you know.
I'm in the corner!
Risky.
Oh, to the rock!
Nice.
Show me the good stuff.
Some bombs, actually nice.
We can try and find secret rooms for that.
Let me see here.
We can try here.
That was my one attempt.
I'll save my last bomb.
I think I'm gonna have to take that blue heart, man.
I could just die, you know, to that boss.
I can...
Oh, actually, I'll take the...
I'll take both.
Fuck it.
Play safe.
Larry!
Yeah, this guy, it's kind of difficult not to take damage again, so I'm glad I took the hearts.
He's unpredictable.
Oh!
He stopped right in front of me.
Wait, they can't go to the edge of the map or something?
Oh, they can, okay.
Oh, he...
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
It's really important that I hold on to this blue heart.
There's another one, though.
That's nice.
I mean, that's a good item.
I could use my...
You know what, let me try.
Plus one damage, plus one lock.
Okay!
Not bad, I guess.
Uh, wait, we don't have a key.
Oh, crap.
I'm not sure there was a key in the shop.
I think there was a bomb?
And that was it.
Yeah.
Break.
Oh, well.
100% demon.
Oh, no, this is gonna be tough.
Oh!
Yeah, one blue heart.
Tinted rocks.
No, oh, but we have these.
Lock should help with this, right?
It doesn't say, so probably not.
That sucks.
We got a step room here.
It's a possibility, depending on what's gonna happen later.
But for now, I will say no.
Whoa, you could...
You could do that with these tears!
Okay, that's pretty sick.
I didn't realize.
That's freaking awesome.
I'm gonna blow these up.
Holy money!
Danke schön.
Now we need a shop.
Dude, this changes everything.
Hey, we could just do that.
That just made this item even better.
Like, way better.
What about up here?
Nothing.
Let's go in here.
What is it with the chemicals?
Increases the damage of tears fired from...
Yeah, sure.
We got so many chemicals.
Sulfuric acid and chemical peel.
What's next?
Oh, there's another one.
There's two of them.
Looks like it's not just the...
Oh, never mind.
My tears are kind of weird.
Sometimes the red shots also break objects.
We got 16 coins.
Hey, that's huge.
Fanny pack.
I like it.
Let's take it.
In fact, can we break this guy as well?
No, you can't.
Good to know.
I'm still gonna check these rooms.
Nothing.
I hope I was right.
And I didn't actually blow something up in there.
I'm pretty sure my shot broke that wall.
Try it on here.
Oh my god.
Blow it to smithereens.
Are you a wizard?
Hetty!
You're a wizard.
I'm a what?
Arcade is calling, except we have no money.
So let's not.
Okay, so wait a minute.
The secret room up top.
It's only attached to one, and the one on the bottom is attached to two.
So I think it doesn't matter, like, where they are.
It is actually just random.
Like, I always thought that it should be either in the center, which is, which it is not.
And, like, the more adjacent rooms the better is what my theory was, you know?
I'm not gonna go in there and spend my coin on that.
Yeah, I will take a peek in here.
Okay.
Let's go up here.
Whoa.
How's my damage?
Five damage is actually pretty good.
Uh, they're gonna take my battery!
Don't you take my battery, you fucker!
I needed that battery!
I'm mad right now, dude.
Fucker.
Ugh.
Monstrosity.
Okay.
Let's hope I get a good item now.
I would love to have used this, uh, active on it.
If it was a shit item.
Watch me get, like, a fucking cube of meat or something, a really bad item.
And...
That's pretty good!
I take that.
Nice!
And we're gonna, we're gonna go full angel, once again.
I like that.
Angel mode has been engaged.
I don't fuck with demons today!
Downpour two.
Wait, why downpour two?
Oh, kill these guys fast!
I have pretty good damage here.
Look for tinted rocks.
Now that we can destroy everything.
Also, just hit the walls.
Nothing.
Dun, dun, dun, dun, dun, dun.
Oh!
I just scared myself a little bit there.
Uh, hookworm, tears traveling us.
Ah, I don't like that very much, man.
It is .48.
Now, I like my shot speed increase that I have from the whipworm.
We have whipworm and hookworm, all the worms.
Could destroy that fire.
Why not?
Wait, I wonder if my tears could have done that as well.
Oh, I didn't realize these guys shot.
I seem to remember those guys don't shoot.
I don't care about enemies, I just want poop.
This is my home now.
We're gonna destroy this bucket.
Look at that.
It's some kind of dangerous liquid that's inside.
That's why I took damage when I ran into it before.
It's not water.
This, I don't know.
Slime.
I think this is gonna become one of my favorite characters.
I just love the idea behind.
If you don't like an item, turn it into stats.
That sounds amazing to me.
Nice!
I'm gonna go in here.
That's unfortunate.
That was rough.
That was a rough room.
We lost one and a half blue hearts there.
Let's see.
Pause.
Wait, so this isn't active.
Uh, let me see.
Triggers the effects of all...
So wait, does that mean I'm gonna do this twice now?
Because I technically used void once before.
Am I gonna get two times void then?
I guess it doesn't matter.
Assuming a passive item grants a permanent stat boost.
Assuming an active item permanently adds its activation effect to voids.
Okay, so if I consume this, I'm gonna use this effect every time I use the void.
Oh, freeze effect ends early if Isaac fires a tear.
That makes sense.
I'm gonna try this.
Wait.
So I didn't get a stat increase so that...
Oh no.
Does that mean I just consumed two actives?
Or did I consume the one I was closest to?
This is confusing right now.
Also, there's a blue heart in here?
How the fuck did I miss that?
Not that... I mean, that was useless just now.
That didn't give me anything.
It's fine.
It's a series of unfortunate happenstances right now.
I can't wait to try this active now.
Is there some hidden active effect on it?
Mom's foot stomps down.
Map has been revealed.
But not the secrets.
Oh, we can get flying here!
The question is...
So it's like...
You gotta decide if you want to sacrifice health for flying.
And for a whole floor, definitely.
Twelve coins.
Duplicates all pickups and item pedestals.
Oh dude, that would void?
It's kind of crazy, no?
That sounds amazing.
Ooh, imagine that.
Wait, single use.
Wait, I wonder if that consumes my void then?
Oh, now I'm not so sure.
That actually makes me think...
Or maybe it just consumes the...
The Plopia effect.
And not the actual...
That's risky, man.
What if I go in again?
No, okay.
Well, we can fly now, so...
Let's kill these first.
What happened?
The fire...
Wait, was I really that low HP?
I'm so confused.
How did that happen?
Okay, once more with this character.
There's clearly things I don't understand.
What?
How did I lose a full heart from that?
Jesus.
Is this character just taking more damage than usual?
If that's the case, then I don't like this character at all.
Then I hate him.
Why did I take a full heart from that?
Oh, man, that was such a good run.
Okay, oh, nice.
We're back.
I can't destroy these anymore.
So sad.
We have eight coins, actually.
I mean, that's good.
And what was this one?
It assumes one red heart.
We had a permanent cube of meat.
And a permanent damage up.
Excavation also grants the anemic effect for the current room.
I don't know what anemic means.
Like, loss of blood, so maybe damage?
You damage yourself?
That doesn't sound good.
Polion versus wrath.
This guy's not scary.
Thank you!
Much appreciated.
And some bombs for me as well.
Not too shabby.
But where is the treasure room?
That's where I want to know.
Keep pooping.
This guy is mobile.
All right.
And here we go.
Oh, we can bomb this.
Watch.
Beautiful.
And a key as well.
This is going really well, by the way.
Many spiders.
Okay, so this is not a bad item, but I would rather just consume it.
Speed and...
Okay, yeah.
I like it.
I love the void effect.
I don't love the fact that I take a full-hearted damage, though.
So that means I'm actually not going to go to the curse room.
Duke of Flies.
Just focus the guy, honestly.
Let's try not to kill the Flies.
Let's just go for him.
I mean, if they're in my way, they're going to get shot.
But other than that...
Is he just going to keep spawning them, or...
I kind of like the strategy.
It's a little bit more risky, I think.
Yeah, look at all these flies.
Yeah, he definitely does not have an upper cap.
He just goes and goes and goes.
Just lost my blue heart, there.
Oh my god!
Please die!
Also, I don't think I took a full-hearted damage, there.
Is that really just when you step on things?
Here's...
Oh, we can't...
We can't convert it, anyway.
So, whatever.
I'll take it.
Obviously, we go here, because it's amazing.
Cheers.
Downpour 1.
Oh, I think I understand what's happening here.
So, if I didn't have a key just now, and I went down the hole, I would have been in whatever that level is, right?
And then when I have a key, I can go straight to Downpour 2.
Skipping Downpour 1.
It doesn't have to come sequentially, you know?
It just happens to be this is where Downpour 1 is, and so on and so forth, you know?
That makes sense to me.
Yeah, we took half a heart.
I do have four bombs.
Oh, look at this.
Sweet!
I'm gonna go for more.
That's too risky.
Thunder Thighs.
Plus one health is nice.
Ice it can break most obstacles...
I mean, we gotta take this.
We are gonna be a little slow, though, so that's a risk.
But it's okay.
We're not that slow.
Point eight is, you know, manageable.
I just love being able to break things by walking on them.
The Thighs have never been stronger.
It's like poor man's Leo.
Oh, god.
I just broke the water bucket.
But I didn't take damage because there's no water in it.
Yeah, look!
Aha!
Not bad.
I can probably not break into secret rooms with this, right?
Ah, bastard.
No, dude.
I'm being fucked here.
Properly spanked.
The range!
Okay, man.
I was like, there's no way he hits me from there.
No keys.
We cannot be standing still against these guys then.
So we're done here?
This is done?
Okay.
No!
Bastards take my battery.
Oh, yeah, I can walk on things.
Don't walk on that one, though.
That's a bomb.
Bad idea.
Let me try and walk into the walls.
I doubt it's gonna work.
Definitely here.
Yes.
Strength.
Nice.
Not bad.
What a nice little floor.
I think it's worth it to take this blue heart.
Now, Jar of Flies.
I kind of want to come back and...
Wait, wait.
Adds a blue fly to the jar for each enemy kill.
Maximum 20 flies can be used in the jar.
I kind of want to come back and use the void on this.
That sounds like a pretty awesome active to have.
But...
Wait, so wait.
Is it passive or not?
It says, adds a blue fly to the jar for each enemy kill.
Ah, I see.
And then using it releases them all.
Okay, okay, okay.
Yeah, I definitely want to do that, I think.
It's like a free Jar of Flies.
This guy's not that tough.
I mean, he's kind of tough, but not that tough.
Last time I fought him, I had much more damage, though.
I'm going to eat these just to have a bit more space.
You shall not hide behind those stones.
I really got a sneeze.
One sec.
There was a fake sneeze.
Oh my god!
Shit!
Oh, we lost demon!
Fuck!
Unfortunate.
Midnight snack!
I think I want that.
I need more health.
I enjoy the midnight snack.
How come food tastes better at night, guys?
It's true, isn't it?
At like two o'clock or two a.m., you open the fridge, you make like a very simple piece of food, and it's just amazing at night.
There's no explanation for that.
Well, shit.
That's fine.
We learned a lesson.
You got to use it first.
All right.
Let's go this way.
That is so funny.
Okay, so I have a theory that when I become flying here, the trade-off is not to take a little bit of damage.
The trade-off is you're going to get one shot.
But I'm not sure.
So what we're going to do, we're going to wait with doing this until the end of the floor.
And just to see if our hearts actually go down, because then there's no risk.
We can move on to the next floor.
This is the test we're going to perform.
Lots of blue hearts.
I would love to throw a bomb in there.
Oh, I thought I could go through...
No.
No key, though.
That's sad.
This guy's special.
He had more health than the others.
Fuck me.
The only one, man.
I can't get in there.
Boss is here.
Got one bomb now.
Treasure room.
Oh, man, I need a key.
I need a key.
I really hope there's a key here.
I can't freaking handle losing another treasure room.
That will kill me.
We have a bomb, but that's just going to reduce our luck.
So I don't know if I want that.
I mean, I'm sure there's some good effect doing that as well.
You know, it's like a trade off.
I just don't know what it is.
Hell yeah.
Very nice.
Time for treasure.
Oh, almost walked into that.
Come here.
Okay, so let me see.
Reveals the map up to two rooms away.
I can't remember.
I have special rooms.
That's all.
That's pretty good.
But if I can also consume it.
Let me see.
I think I'm going to consume it.
Luck and shot.
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know if that was worth it.
Shit.
It may not have been worth it.
I mean, it is RNG, right?
Oh, yeah, let's break all these.
Not that one.
There's water in it.
Oh, shit.
What's happening here, guys?
What are y'all up to?
Why is there so many items in here?
Oh, wait, I can get...
I didn't mean to buy that.
Oh, no, I didn't buy it.
It was just...
It happened to be a lucky one.
Moms block brings luck, spawns a trinket, doubles the effects of trinkets.
I like it.
I do, but it isn't active.
So maybe not, actually.
Another one?
What the fuck?
Sure.
I mean, okay.
Uh, I could use it once to spawn a trinket.
And then when I do that, it's going to transfer to that, right?
Monkey paw spawns two black hearts when Isaac is reduced to half a heart.
The trinket is consumed after triggering three types.
I like that.
That means we're going to keep getting trinkets, right?
When we use this now.
Let me see what else there was with it.
Spawns the trinkets, doubles the effects of trinkets.
So nice.
My trinket is really good now.
I'm going to buy this as well.
Okay.
Pause time.
Oh, better heal up.
Wish me luck.
It's like a water dancer.
I like the sound effect of that attack.
It's satisfying.
Oh my god.
Clean.
Absolutely clean.
Well, we have to take this.
So, I unfortunately cannot bomb my way into that room up there.
And we're going to go for angels, so fuck the demons.
So I guess we just go down?
Unless we go back and try to find another bomb.
I think the shop may have had another bomb, actually.
I could be wrong.
Let's double check.
No, no, no, no bomb in here.
But there could be a bomb in that, but I don't have money for it.
So, you know, it is what it is.
Okay.
Anything else need to do here?
We have one bomb.
Oh, I wanted to check the...
See how many hearts I get if I run into that fire.
Ooh, they become transparent!
Look at that!
I can fly, but I am going to die, right?
This is like the trade-off.
Okay.
I wonder if I can still eat rocks.
I am not going to walk into those buckets, though.
This is kind of risky.
And I can't heal up.
Okay.
At least we confirmed that.
And so now that effect should be gone, right?
Let's see here.
Wait, we still have the effect!
What?
Why, why, why?
No, we are done!
We are going to die.
Focus!
This is the worst trade in history!
I don't want to fly anymore!
I take it back.
Okay, I do want to fly.
Wait.
Oh, wait.
Flying is gone.
Oh,
I ate the mushroom.
Right.
Okay.
Give me the coin.
But I am going to...
Okay, nice.
Puberty.
Strength.
I think I am going to keep strength.
Dagaz is going to give us one soul.
No, actually, we have 33% demon or angel chance.
I think I should use this just to get a buffer.
Yeah, let's do that.
I am also not going to run into those mushrooms because I may take damage from that.
Shit!
Fuck!
Damn, son.
Is that a lucky rock?
Rocks and other obstacles have a chance to drop.
Dude, that's a crazy synergy with me.
Monkey paw...
I mean, I will never be reduced to half a heart anyway.
Who cares?
Sick.
Can I grab this as well?
Can I be cheeky?
I don't want to risk it.
We are going to lose angel chance if I take damage now.
Oh, shit.
I am scared.
I am hiding over here.
Dude.
Kill him.
Nah!
He had to get me with that last volley.
Fucking asshole.
Duh!
Oh, it feels horrible.
I am going to eat these now just because...
Fuck.
I am eating them all.
I am tilt eating mushrooms.
Nice!
I am getting some money at least.
I need these angels to bless my soul.
I need more damage.
This is getting ridiculous.
We need to do drive-bys here.
That was beautifully handled.
Honestly, that was good stuff.
Yeah, why not?
That's for you.
Totally worth.
Come at me.
Okay.
Now give me a shot.
Kill it.
Nice.
Okay, man.
We are getting money.
Fuck!
I hate these guys with a passion.
Why do I get so many of these when I play this character?
They are just out here to steal and ruin my day.
Vibes are ruined now.
Okay.
You know what?
Let's kill the boss.
Get him out of here.
I need to let out some anger.
I got six bombs.
Oh, he blocked me, the little fucker!
I am never going to try that again.
I cannot figure out how to do bombs.
Get away from me.
Like, dude, give me delirium over this guy any day of the week.
Some of these bosses are just insane.
I cannot take damage.
He is too fucking strong.
That's good.
I like Binky.
Binky, I am a fan of.
We got bombs as well.
We can gain entrance here.
Let's remember to keep two bombs at all times.
Do not consume more than two bombs.
Good stuff.
Okay, so check it.
Let me remember, what did I do?
So, I used an item earlier.
What did I do?
I got something out of it.
That's going to happen now.
I forgot which item that was, honestly.
But I kind of want to take this, use it, and then come back and use my other item.
Pretty much.
Let me see.
What was it?
Why is the timing?
Okay.
We have an issue here.
I, uh, we can't actually do that.
Unless I go here.
Here.
Wire.
I don't know why I'm thinking of that right now.
Unidentified pill.
I think I'm good here.
So now, if I use it now, I should be using...
Wait, if...
Okay, so wait.
Now that has been consumed, right?
So now that is in my void.
So the next time I use void, we're gonna use the...
Back in time, you know.
Power tools, pretty much.
And I think that's pretty much it.
Yep.
Good shit.
Let's try it.
When we have energy.
I don't want to go in there.
Place makes me sad.
Like,
this room is chaos.
Like, nobody can do this room.
How do you do this room?
This is worse than anything else in the game.
You know what it is?
It's too frickin' chaotic and random, these rooms.
Million enemies just shooting randomly at random times.
It is the hardest thing for me to deal with.
We're gonna die.
Hematemesis is my nemesis.
You can't tell me anything different, sis.
This guy needs to die now.
There we go.
Come here.
I could walk into those shrooms.
Yeah.
Actually, it's a bad idea.
Oh, but wait.
Some of these shrooms have bites out of them.
Maybe it's the one...
Maybe it's the one that have been bitten that don't explode?
Huh?
Maybe?
We don't have enough data points, but it could be.
That guy's just standing still.
Mysterious liquid.
Tears leave creep where they land?
Creep...
30 damage per second?
Are you for real?
Wait, we need less range.
But I guess if I hit an enemy, it's gonna drop liquids at their feet, right?
So we're good.
What?
This seems insane.
30 damage per second?
That's wild.
These guys are flying, so that's not gonna affect them.
I do like the radioactive effect on my tears.
You know what I could do?
I could go in here.
If I don't like it, I revert time.
That should give me the heart back, right?
But it also consumes my things, so...
Not so sure about that.
Let's grab this heart in here.
And this one, what was that?
Uh, spawns a black heart.
Wait a minute!
I have an idea.
You ready?
Can we go here?
Wait, no, no.
If I do this, I have to...
Then I get a black heart, and then I'm gonna lose one half black heart on the way out.
No, it's a bad idea.
I miscalculated things.
I have done a goof.
This is not worth it.
Gimme that.
Let's just heal up and leave.
How about that?
We spend enough time here.
Maybe look for secrets.
We got four bombs.
Actually, I think this could be it here.
Fuck, yeah, dude!
Ah!
I need to go grab that heart before I eat those pills.
It's too risky.
All right.
Put your gambling pants on.
Strap in, people.
It's gonna be a wild one.
Get ready.
I'm eating those...
Oh, where am I going?
We're eating pills.
We need one more puberty.
Recharges, I guess.
I think I'm gonna use this card.
I need that healing.
We also have the gambling room.
We could check that out.
Okay, please.
I think I'm gonna blow up one of these.
Shit.
No healing, unfortunately.
Let's do this one.
Yes!
And now we gamble.
This is good.
Beautiful.
Man, those keys are so wonderful right now.
We shouldn't gamble all the money, though.
Two bombs.
Not too shabby.
Whoa!
We're gonna make this money multiply.
Why is gambling so fun?
Oh my god!
Fully healed!
Now I regret using the card, but then again, you couldn't have known, right?
Anything would have killed me, so I was just too afraid.
Can we go step, even?
We can go to the curse room!
Let's do it!
Hells yeah!
Ah, I keep going the wrong way here.
I look like a rock rat.
Okay.
All right.
Not too shabby.
Could be worse.
I was kind of hoping for a pedestal in there, so I could have used my...
You know?
Abba, wait, every time I do that, it's gonna...
Wait, we actually have a problem.
If I use this...
If I use my void now to transform a passive into stats, I'm gonna get sent back to the start of the room.
Abba, wait, I can leave the room and come back.
We're good, we're good, we're good.
I think we're good.
Everything's fine.
Don't panic.
We got it.
Maybe.
Scatole!
So wait, let me see.
If I use this now, I need to calculate.
So if I go out of this room and come back in...
Right?
I pick up this...
I know, I know, I know.
We pick up this...
No, wait, I miscalculated.
Yeah, you actually can't do it with passive items then.
But you can't do it with active items.
That's fine.
It's okay.
I fucked it up a little bit.
Yo, I forgot we had this effect.
Richness.
Oh, yeah.
That is awesome.
I don't want to step into that one.
I mean, money's not going to be an issue.
Eh, you know what we could also do?
Place a bomb, look for a secret room.
If it's not, revert time.
That's a thing.
But yeah, I'm just throwing ideas out there, you know?
Okay, let's build the shit out of this.
Lovely.
I mean, money's not going to be a problem in this run.
Money is saved, or solved.
Okay, so mines.
This place is unique.
There's buttons here that I don't understand.
Whoa, okay then.
We just lost a lot of Angel.
That is unfortunate.
Rip my Angel Dreams.
No,
we didn't.
We're good.
Let's try that again.
Dude, we need a buffer.
There's no way I can do this without taking damage.
Oh, what is this?
Oh, god.
Yeah, there's no way.
I feel like this green stuff on the floor ain't doing shit.
Oh, nice.
Holy water?
And something we don't know what is.
Uh, shadows upon hitting an enemy.
I mean, that's good, actually.
I'd take that.
I like it.
We got meats on wheels.
Meals on wheels.
Should I eat the mushroom, man?
I'm tempted to eat the mushroom.
I'll do it.
No, it's not a real shop!
How sad is that?
Okay, I think the green stuff on the floor did work just now.
There's no way my 3.5 damage just did that on its own.
Because that was crazy.
Oh, thanks.
Even though I can't just eat them.
I'm scared of this thing blowing up in my hand.
I don't know if that's going to happen.
I'm just going to throw it.
Well, that was dumb.
Never do that.
How on earth are you going to do this room?
Kill it!
I'm in so much trouble.
Revert!
God damn it!
Uh...
Yeah, just keep doing it.
This room is so difficult!
Again.
Wait, can I just keep doing this?
There's only three charges on it, though, or something.
Oh my God.
We go again.
Until we get it right.
It's insane how difficult this room is!
Wait, what?
Oh, I should have just done that.
Well, there you go.
How about that?
Ain't that some shit?
I feel kind of dumb right now.
Got healing as well.
That's great.
More money.
71.
I need a shot, but I need it now.
We can actually gamble forever, pretty much.
Unless it blows up.
I'm going to be ready to push the bomb away if there's a bomb coming out.
You know what?
I like that.
That's going to produce creeps on the floor, closer to where I am.
The cope is real.
More energy.
Oi!
This guy wants...
Okay, so here, check it out.
What we can do here...
One more after this.
Beautiful.
Exactly as planned.
You may ask yourself, how did I know that was going to happen?
And I'm going to tell you, that's a secret.
You will never know.
It is a secret that only I know about.
The result of many years in the monastery.
Motherfucker.
Can I eat that?
No, I can probably not eat that card.
I kind of want you to do this.
Yeah, just take me back.
Try that again.
Oh, those spiders are considered armored, I think.
Hargalas would work against them.
Oh, no.
Yeah, how are you even going to dodge that?
That's just impossible.
A key.
Am I not going to take damage if I walk on this?
Yeah, see, I don't like that.
One was fine, two...
Not too much.
This horn fells.
He likes his bombs.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
What is that?
Get that away from me.
Oh, man.
I may not survive this.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
I'm having some trouble here.
Yeah!
Wait, brimstone bombs has appeared.
That sounds awesome.
Good.
Sacrifice health to go into the creepy area?
I think so, actually.
Why not?
It's not a lot of HP we have here.
This may have been a mistake.
Mosulium.
100% demon is what this is.
I didn't expect me to just walk into those stones, did you now?
That's right.
I eat all the stones.
Oh, that's huge.
More bombs for moi.
That's a bomb right there.
I'm going to refrain from eating that.
You got a telepathic bastard?
This is the guy that stole the tinted rock from me last time.
I think it's about time we exchange this trinket.
Not going to be too much useful anymore.
I juked them unintentionally.
That was nice.
Getting blue hearts from these rocks, though, is kind of really nice.
Shit.
Okay, reset that one.
Try again.
More blue hearts, please.
Let's go here.
Careful, there's bombs here.
I take damage from the laser also, like when it comes towards me.
I need hearts.
Red hearts.
That's looking okay, actually.
It's not too bad.
The green liquor on the floor combined with the holy water is a great combo.
Really nice.
Best bot is going to take us to two out of three.
Sponsor fly familiar with the current room.
I could also turn into stats.
But no, let's go two out of three on the Beelzebub.
I'm not sure what three out of three does with Beelzebub.
I guess we'll find out.
Yep, yep, yep.
We missed the room.
It's like a little brimstone.
99 coins.
Watch out!
Haggle us!
Old... oh yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I have many coins for you, friend.
We're going to have a lot of fun together.
We're going to be spending a lot of time together as well.
Nice!
I take that.
I do wonder though, so let's say I go or I revert time, come back in here.
I wonder if the gambling is going to be the exact same sequence of items you get from it.
Because if it is and everything's deterministic, then you can make some crazy plays.
Let's say that.
All right, not that it matters now.
I'm infinitely money, you know.
Come on.
I'm going to give this guy some.
This is going to give me batteries though, right?
Oh, uh, automatically restores.
Yeah, actually.
I think I like that.
I've had enough of that rock.
Okay, he's a little different.
He doesn't just, okay, he does give me battery as well.
We can get two charges out of it.
Or two full charges.
Does he give me an item at some point though?
This is what I want to know.
Maybe at some point he poops out an actual item for me and not just battery.
He does!
Oh, it's this thing.
Okay, so check it out.
This is an active.
I think it's an active.
No, no, no.
This is not the active.
This is the one that's not an active.
So I'm going to leave this room.
I'll come back and I'm going to use this thing on it.
Oh, uh, ooh, eee.
I see the issue.
Yeah, uh, thanks.
That's not very nice.
How about some hearts, man?
Come on, heal me.
That's what I'm really here for.
Not a single heart so far.
That's almost $50 spent.
If you don't give me hearts, I will haggle at you.
Oh, a door in the lower stages has opened or higher stages.
Show me the health.
Oh, nice.
That could have been the end right there.
This is why you keep shooting.
Where are my hearts at?
It's just not going to happen, is it?
Is anything but hearts?
I mean, he's showing me a heart.
There we go.
Another heart has been shown.
Yes!
Well, there we go.
I think it's time we blow shit up.
It was nice knowing you.
Move on.
This guy's attack is so fast.
Oh, kill that immediately before it spawns.
I really should be looking for secrets, I guess.
Step into my creep!
This guy just can't die, it seems.
Huh?
I'm tempted to reset the room.
Okay, reset.
Terrible.
Reset that shit.
This guy has a very high rate of fire.
It's disturbing.
Oh, the creep!
Okay, much better.
Yeah, look, the exact same items in the chest as well.
It is all deterministic.
Haven't found the shop room yet, though.
That's really messed up.
We got to find the shop with this amount of money.
Oh, god, I'm scared.
There we go.
I'm gonna eat all these.
Of course, I don't have the rock anymore, but maybe, you know, a heart is in here.
I think this may be a secret.
There we go!
Ten percent angel!
Why?
I'm not gonna complain, that's awesome!
Keep destroying those things in the future.
Could it be another one here?
Maybe they can't be right next to each other.
Oh, they destroyed these fires.
Oh, these guys are so difficult.
I need homing tears.
That was a rough room.
Bad gas.
Yeah, protect my angel.
Let's destroy these as well.
If I go in there, I'm gonna lose HP, but I can teleport back in case I don't like it.
Let's see what we get in here.
Yeah, I don't like it, so we go back.
Not for me.
These fires are gonna mess with me.
Okay, one of them down.
Nice.
Oh, they're making a minefield in here.
My damage is pathetic.
If enemies are flying, I'm gonna have a bad time.
This is the current situation.
Come on.
Honestly, I handled this room pretty well.
Jesus, come on.
Thank you.
Careful, don't eat the bomb.
What the hell is this?
Ah, it's kind of gonna throw rocks.
You bastard.
I could just destroy the rocks and then he won't have any ammo.
No, it's a fake shop.
See, my damage is really good against non-flying enemies.
And of course, the rich get richer.
This is the rule of Isaac.
We have 20 bombs.
Let's just start bombing shit out of things.
Maybe over here.
I can try down here, I guess.
Let's try this one.
I don't think I did.
Okay, let's do curse room.
Oh, no, wait.
This was the bad.
We don't like this room.
True.
I was like, yeah, let's unexplored on the map.
Haven't been there.
Back to the boss.
I kind of hate that I used the hourglass on my portal, or my void thingy.
It's pretty much useless now for certain things.
I can't really use it, you know?
It was a bad calculation.
The heretic.
These guys are making... Okay.
He's flying, unfortunately, so it's gonna take us approximately 19 million years to kill him.
I don't think I can beat him, guys.
Maybe Hagalas does something to him?
No, okay.
Oh, fuck.
Jesus.
Yeah, we're dead.
It was a good run.
How did I get hit by that, man?
I was out of range.
Shit.
Oh, shit.
Lock in.
Oh, no.
Yeah, I don't... sure.
Whatever you say, buddy.
That's it for today.
Rage quit at this.
I can't stand that boss.
Like, when he does the fires all over the room, it is actually impossible to predict where the lasers are gonna be.
I have no idea.
But we did manage to beat the delirium today, so that's something.
The plan was to do a challenge, but then I got absorbed by the new character that I saw.
And even though that run didn't go so well and the others with this guy, I think he may actually be one of my favorite characters now.
I just love the premise behind this active.
The floors are hard.
Yeah, they are, right?
You would have won if you had good... yeah, but that's just like saying, yeah, you would have won if you had better items.
And that's always the case like this.
Bye, Oliver.
I gotta go.
See you later, ender tricks.
Thanks for stopping by.
I'm gonna put on my, for next time, look at Mega Satan ending.
I was saying that.
To-do list.
Mega... Satan... Mega Stan ending.
I like Stan.
Misspelling.
Dude, you've heard about Stan.
Get ready for Mega Stan.
The creator, Isaac, also helped create Super Meat Boy.
Really?
So it wasn't crazy, right?
That was a reference to Super Meat Boy.
The missing tooth and everything, it was almost too on point.
Yeah, right?
Please do not neglect Bethany, but I hate Bethany.
I hate her gimmick.
I don't think it's fun.
But, I mean, eventually I will play all the characters.
Because you get all those achievements on them, right?
It's kind of satisfying to fill that little page out.
What do you hate about it?
I don't know, she just feels weak.
Her item, her act of feels way too gimmicky.
I always forget you're like so far from gaming culture.
Wait, what do you mean?
I'm very much in the gaming culture.
I've been gaming all my life.
Cleveland has been successfully unlocked today.
I kind of wish it had set Cleveland.
We should make a mod and rename one of the areas to Cleveland.
That was so funny.
You just need to not take damage with her.
Yeah, I mean, you're not wrong.
I agree with you.
Oliver is a Nordic OG who played Hugo back in the day.
I did!
I did play Hugo.
Hugo the Jungle Beast, right?
Does that translation make sense in English?
No, the Jungle Animal.
Jungle?
Wait, is that Hugo?
Maybe I'm mixing things up right now.
Really should play Subnautica.
I have already played it, Taren.
It's on my YouTube channel, go check it out.
I played Subnautica and Below Zero.
And I loved them.
And I'm looking forward to playing Subnautica 2 when it's fully released, not just Early Access.
I just got home from work.
Can you upload 3-hour 30-minute VOD instantly to YouTube?
Thanks.
Yes, I can.
It'll happen almost instantly.
It has to upload first.
I will of course play GTA 6, man.
Obviously.
I'm a huge Grand Theft Auto fan.
I say that, but then I'm maybe also a fake fan, because I never really played Grand Theft Auto 4.
And I say never really, I did play the beginning, the very beginning, back when I had a shitty computer and I couldn't run it.
That game ran like ass on my PC.
This is why I just didn't want to handle it.
I couldn't deal with it.
But nowadays, I should be able to run it, no problem.
With us or by yourself.
You're talking about Grand Theft Auto?
With you guys, of course.
And I feel like Grand Theft Auto could be a game that would be fun to play with chat.
Meaning where I don't just ignore chat, you know?
Because what are you really going to spoil in that game?
Especially if we do it on release day, you know?
Could be fun to play live.
It's just all around fun.
Like those games are just silly, you know?
Silly games with silly characters doing silly things.
So that could be a fun thing to try.
As a vaulter needs to ask, when you say, Yup, yup, yup, is that land before time coded?
I don't even know what you're talking about.
So I don't think it is?
Wait, unless...
Are you thinking about the cartoon with the dinosaurs?
Because if that's the case, then I think it may be.
I just didn't realize it.
Yeah!
It is, then!
Dude, that was so deep in my brain!
If you hadn't said that, I don't think I would have realized why I'm saying that.
It is from that.
How much do you care about the GTA story?
I mean, not that much.
It's like watching a comedy movie, you know?
The story is not always fantastic, but it's fun.
Except it's not the main draw at all.
The main draw of Grand Theft Auto is, you know, driving away from cops and doing silly things and interacting with silly characters and just exploring a world that is so detailed, you know?
Like a living city.
That's the main draw for me, at least.
Are games for the vote drawn from the backlog on the side?
So when I do a vote, and it's not always, but when I do, I just go through the backlog and I pick like, I don't know, five to ten games.
That seemed interesting to me at the time that I want to play, you know?
Like maybe I'm in a sci-fi mode right now.
I'm on a sci-fi kick.
So I just pick some of those stuff that looks interesting, you know?
And then I just put them on a pole and then I let you guys decide if I can't decide.
If there's a game that I really want to play, I just play it.
So it's mostly if I'm a little undecided anyway, I just let you guys, you know...
Add the extra at the end.
There's not a vote right now.
Yeah, I think Isaac was part of a vote, wasn't it?
I don't remember if it was.
Isaac won a vote, right?
Or did I just decide to play it?
I forgot.
Yeah, it was a vote.
Okay.
Teren, I am going to play Minecraft with bots next time I play Minecraft.
Season three will be with mods.
And it's most likely going to be Create, I think.
Apparently something big happened with Create lately.
Something about flying machines or whatever.
It's like a whole new thing, you know?
So now it's like massive or something.
Aeronautics, exactly.
Oh, it's a separate mod?
I thought it was like just another update to that.
What happened with Half-Life 2?
Half-Life 2 is a game that I never did finish.
I think I got halfway through it or so, maybe less.
And this was, we're talking maybe 15 years ago, guys.
So that's why I put it on pause.
It simply means it's a game I want to return to one day and play.
Most likely though, I'm going to replay Half-Life 1 and 2.
If Half-Life 3 comes out, you know, just to get ready for it.
And not always to happen.
Sometimes I finish the games before I upload to YouTube.
Other times I'm like five to ten episodes ahead.
And then, for example, with Red Dead Redemption that I'm playing right now on YouTube, I'm actually having a lot of fun being just one episode ahead at a time.
People have been really nice not to spoil anything.
Also because it's a game that's, I guess, a little harder to spoil.
You know, it's just been fun to see what people are saying and reading comments and keeping up with that.
So it depends on the game and how much I'm playing it.
Please do it.
Half-Life 3 is coming.
Genius.
People have been saying that for like ten years.
I didn't mean to say that sarcastically.
His name is Genius.
France.
Yeah, yeah, the Hopium is very real.
This time it's coming out for sure.
I mean, if they ever release Half-Life 3 with that title, it's going to be a money machine.
So I can't imagine that it never does happen.
Like it should happen at some point, right?
Maybe together with the Steamframe, you know, when the Steamframe comes, maybe they decide to release that and the Steam machine and Half-Life 3 do like a triple whammy combo.
Did you finish your PhD?
I did not.
I stopped a little over halfway through to pursue this stuff instead.
And honestly, I'm happy I did.
This is great.
Who knows?
Maybe if I get cancelled in the future for saying something I shouldn't and everything burns up and goes to shit, I can be like, yeah, you know what?
Maybe I'll go back to finishing the PhD and then I'll do that instead.
We're all heroes until we're all villains or something.
What is that quote from Batman?
You know?
Like that door comment?
Wait, what door comment?
Oh, the one with the peepee, man?
Putting the peepee in the hole?
I don't think that's cancel worthy.
But yeah, something like that, I guess.
You can just pause it.
I mean, pause and pause.
You work on a project, right?
And you can always like start a new project later on.
Like there's no rules there.
You just got to, you know, get a new PhD position.
That's the hard part, right?
Writing applications and actually getting the job.
But you could, in theory.
Nothing prevents you from doing multiple PhDs as well if you want to.
What I mean by pause is, I already started working on a project, right?
So I would continue that project.
But who knows?
Maybe I wouldn't.
I'm also not a big fan of the whole academia lifestyle, honestly, after I've been through it a little bit.
It wasn't really something I vibe with very much.
So most likely, if I end up not doing YouTube in the future for whatever reason, I'll probably just find a job in the private sector.
Which is most likely going to be AI related right at that time.
Since that's pretty much what all of software is nowadays.
What did you study?
I studied physics.
With a specialty in astrophysics.
So technically, my master's was with a specialty in astrophysics.
And then I started a PhD in astrophysics as well, working at dark in Copenhagen.
It's like a research group that focuses on all the dark stuff in the universe.
Dark matter, dark energy, you know, expansion of the universe, stuff like that.
Say something smart, something smart.
You'll do ice extremes forever, though?
No!
At some point, I will finish the game.
Trust.
I will get all the achievements.
I will be done.
And we can move on to other great things in life.
Yeah,
but holding a PhD is for life while YouTube is finite?
I don't know.
I guess I don't really care too much about that.
I mean, I'm going to get a job no matter what, you know.
Maybe I'll get paid a little bit more if I have a PhD in the... or on the CV, but it's fine.
And if you have a PhD, this is the good thing.
You can eat all the pills in the world with no adverse side effects.
Maybe I'll get a false PhD.
Love your stream so much you're entertaining like an addict at this point?
Well, I'm also an addict at playing games, so this is a great symbiosis to the electronic.
But thank you for saying that.
I appreciate it.
What's the time in Denmark?
It is 19.21.
19.22, right now.
So anywhere in the Discord server, I can suggest a game.
Yeah, you can suggest it in the channel-related server.
Or just here, I mean, just don't send me a DM.
That's all.
That's the only thing, because I get so many, and I really feel bad not responding to them, because I just get so many.
I can't do it.
It's much easier if we consolidated in one spot, and then I sometimes go in there and I take a look, you know?
Darkest Dungeon?
I want to play this.
I'd love to see you play Void Stranger.
Is that the one with the telescope thingy?
No, that's not it.
That's something else.
But that one is on my list, though.
I remember the name.
It's on my backlog.
Speaking of backlog...
Boom.
That's the backlog.
By the way, I'm working on making a backlog just like the one I just linked.
But for everyone.
Right now, you can make accounts, you can add your own games, you can share your profile, but it's not supposed to be like a backlogged competitor.
This is a much different sort of scope.
This is no bloat, no social stuff, no friends following each other or leaving comments.
It is just simple, snappy, fast, easy to use, and no bloat, you know?
So that's like the intention with that.
Very simple design, very limited in scope.
Yeah.
It's working really well so far, but I really want to get it working very well until I put it out there, you know, because security is a big thing.
So I'm trying to work on patching every single hole that could be right there, you know?
Even though the only sort of user data that could be leaked if shit goes wrong is, you know, your game selection, which is not, you know, that crazy.
Yeah, I hate bloat as well.
Yeah, there's email verification, there's password reset right now, there's multi-factor authentication, that works as well.
I even have options for downloading all your data in CSV files and JSON files, whatever you want.
On every data I have, or all the data there is about, you can download it down, you know, to see exactly what we store about you.
You should ask for H verification.
No, you mean like, hey, upload your passport, please.
Create an API so I can integrate it into my app.
What would you like to pull from the API though, Tabin?
Give me an example of what you would use it for.
Because I actually can't imagine what you mean by that.
I mean, I could.
Two ways sync it with the app.
Oh, you mean like, so like, if you have a list of games already, you sort of want to upload it directly or...
Important export, I mean, yeah, that could be a thing.
But you don't really need an API for that.
It could just be an option on the side, right?
Passwords are stored in plaintext?
No, no, no.
It's all hashed, don't worry.
I don't even see them.
I'm not like, I don't even have access to that.
It's all stored in Superbase.
A JSON parser?
Yeah, something like that.
It wouldn't be hard either to just...
I mean, what you can do right now is when you make a list of games that you have in your backlog, you can download your game list as a JSON right now so you can see what the file structure is or how you need to structure it.
And then you just do the same thing.
Maybe you write your own script and you have a list of games you want to add.
It will, you know, make it into the JSON format, you upload it, and then it can just import all the games.
I guess that works.
I have a native app for movies, and I'm thinking about adding games to it, which is basically your backlog, so I can add your app to sync with it.
Oh, that's a cool idea.
Are you talking about jelly fin or something?
Or what kind of app are you talking about?
Do you do sports?
Ah, I don't, man.
I wish I did.
I want to be more active.
The closest sport that I do, that I don't do very often, but I do sometimes, is badminton.
And also climbing.
But that's very rare.
I think the last time I did that was half a year ago, so...
What's the monetization strategy?
No, strategy!
I will just be paying for it out of pocket.
Not that it's going to be a lot of money, assuming that we don't get, like, a million users.
I'm assuming, like, you know, a thousand users.
It's fine.
Yeah, bouldering.
Not climbing climbing.
I don't go out and just climb trees or something.
Bouldering is so much fun, guys.
Highly recommended.
Try swimming?
I'm not a big fan of it.
And it's going to sound stupid, but I don't like going to the pool.
Like, you go into the changing room, there's all these old farts, and they're all, because it's Denmark, they just do that here.
The cocks hanging out, you know, walking around.
It's just, you get, I don't know, the floor is nasty.
It's, I don't know.
It's not for me.
And it sounds crazy, but that's what it's like over here, man.
I just don't like it.
Now, if I had a nice lake somewhere, that is like, not too nasty, then I could see myself going for a swim.
I think it's like that everywhere, okay.
I mean, some countries have, you know, less issues with nudity, and everyone's just sort of, don't give a fuck, especially the old people.
They're so old, they don't care anymore.
They have their ding dong hanging out, you know, butt naked.
They stand right next to you.
They don't care at all.
I don't know, it's weird.
Here in Finland, it's against the rules to wear a bathing suit and a sauna.
I mean, that's also weird to do.
Why would you do that?
The sauna is supposed to be a naked thing, right?
I mean, maybe a towel is what you would use, if anything.
But probably not even that.
I come back to the stream and Oliver's talking about nudity.
I am!
Yeah, I don't think you should go in there with clothes on.
It's a bad idea.
I don't know if it's dangerous, is it?
It's going to be nasty.
You're going to be sweating in that, and it's going to be...
sauna is sacred, no clothing allowed.
Yeah, I would say so.
Guys, I'm out of here.
Thanks for watching.
It's time for me to go.
And of course, we have on the agenda some Red Dead Redemption, for those that are following that.
Amazing game, by the way.
Red Dead Redemption 1.
So look forward to that one.
Have a good day.
Bye-bye.